<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course on Nothing to see here</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course on Nothing to see here</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© [Jim Greer](https://jbgreer.github.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:33:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computational Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/computational-linear-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:33:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/computational-linear-algebra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rob-101-computational-linear-algebrahttpsroboticsumicheduacademicscoursescourse-offeringsrob101-fall-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robotics.umich.edu/academics/courses/course-offerings/rob101-fall-2020/&#34;&gt;ROB 101: Computational Linear Algebra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computational Linear Algebra is a pilot first-semester, first-year undergraduate course that will show how mathematics and computation are unified for reasoning about data and making discoveries about the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linear algebra and coding are rapidly becoming an essential foundation for the modern engineer in a computational world.  Students in this course will gain insights into the mathematical theory of linear algebra and its realization in practical computational tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theoretical Minimum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-theoretical-minimum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 17:24:11 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-theoretical-minimum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-theoritical-miniumum-httpstheoreticalminimumcom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theoreticalminimum.com/&#34;&gt;The Theoritical Miniumum &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Theoretical Minimum is a series of Stanford Continuing Studies courses taught by world renowned physicist Leonard Susskind.  These courses collectively teach everything required to gain a basic understanding of each area of modern physics including all of the fundamental mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sequence begins with the modern formulations of classical mechanics discovered by Lagrange and Hamilton in the late 18th and 19th centuries, and then moves on to the radical new theories of relativity and quantum mechanics discovered by Albert Einstein and others in the early 20th century.  The sequence concludes with a study of modern cosmology including the physics of black holes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art and Science of PCB Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-art-and-science-of-pcb-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:35:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-art-and-science-of-pcb-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-and-science-of-pcb-designhttpspcbmitedu&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pcb.mit.edu&#34;&gt;The Art and Science of PCB Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the official course website for the MIT IAP 2025 PCB Design Class! MIT students interested in taking the course should fill out this form. Those who are not MIT students or unable to join us during IAP 2025, but still interested in learning the basics of PCB design, can check out our course archives which has materials, labs, and recorded lectures from previous offerings of the class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient ML</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/efficient-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 16:10:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/efficient-ml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tinyml-and-efficient-deep-learning-computinghttpsefficientmlai&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://efficientml.ai&#34;&gt;TinyML and Efficient Deep Learning Computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MIT 6.5940 Fall 2024 course focuses on efficient machine learning and systems. This is a crucial area as deep neural networks demand extraordinary levels of computation, hindering its deployment on everyday devices and burdening the cloud infrastructure. This course introduces efficient AI computing techniques that enable powerful deep learning applications on resource-constrained devices. Topics include model compression, pruning, quantization, neural architecture search, distributed training, data/model parallelism, gradient compression, and on-device fine-tuning. It also introduces application-specific acceleration techniques for large language models and diffusion models. Students will get hands-on experience implementing model compression techniques and deploying large language models (Llama2-7B) on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
